

Stephanie Hotz Senior art director | UX/UI designer

> PROFILE

I'm Stephanie, a senior art director, UX/UI designer and interdisciplinary concepter based in Berlin, Germany.

I believe in a natural and inventive culture where the work of multi-disciplinary thinkers can come together and find its way into society.

I always focus on the user's experience in the specific context of each project – whether for an artwork, branding and/or a digital service. I'm here to generate great user experiences that solve everyday problems.

> SERVICES

BRANDING > Creative and art direction > Concept and visual design

> Brand and corporate design > Packaging > Finishing

> Production and supervision

UX/UI DESIGN > User journeys and user flows > User Personas

> Information architecture > Usability testing and analysis

> Wireframing and rapid prototyping > UI components and documentation

> Asset creation and developer handouts

> TOOLSET

> Adobe CS / Sketch / Balsamiq / InVision / Figma / Zeplin / Slack and more

> EXPERIENCE

07/2018 - PRESENT Senior art director and UX/UI designer working for corporates, institutions and agencies

11/2014 - 06/2018

Senior art director working for corporates, institutions and agencies on concept, branding, packaging, campaigning, finishing, supervision and project management

02/2008 - 10/2014 Visual designer & art director

01/2007 – 02/2008 Junior art director @Jung von Matt/Alster Werbeagentur GmbH, Hamburg, Germany

SINCE 2006 – PRESENT Art projects, exhibitions, grants and granted residencies

> EDUCATION

04/2018 - 07/2018 UX designer @CareerFoundry

02/2008 - 10/2009 Graduate studies "Fine arts" Bauhaus-University Weimar, Germany

04/2005 - 04/2006 Exchange studies "Intermedia arts" Tokyo University of the Arts, Tokyo, Japan

09/2003 – 04/2004 Exchange studies "Visual design" EINA – Escola de Disseny y Arte, Barcelona, Spain

10/1999 – 09/2006 Diploma studies "Fine arts" Bauhaus-University Weimar, Germany

> LANGUAGES

- > German = native > English = C1
- > French, spanish = B1 > Japanese = A2